Matthew Clifford

Front-End Developer

Email: matthewclifford@hotmail.co.uk

Tel: +44 7708 913 089 Address: Hertfordshire, UK

Portfolio: https://mjclifford.com/ GitHub: https://github.com/BuenVia

PERSONAL PROFILE

Matthew is a self-taught Front-End Developer with a robust foundation in HTML, CSS and JavaScript, as well as currently acquiring knowledge of frameworks such as React JS, to accompany BootStrap and SCSS.

Having been inspired by building projects using Python, Matthew took to Web Development as his chosen field after recognising the need to improve a family member's business' website. Since then 100s of hours have gone into learning and development with a determined desire to move into professional web development.

Matthew Currently works as a Tourism Health & Safety Specialist, having become a highly qualified specialist in his field. Throughout his career, he has worked extensive periods in more than 30 countries, including living in Madrid, Spain where he became fluent in Spanish.

Mathew's portfolio can be found at https://mjclifford.com/ where a list of projects can be found.

TECHNOLOGY SUMMARY

HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, React JS, Node JS, BootStrap, SCSS, MongoDB, SQL, PHP, Python

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR H&S SPECIALIST

<u>Expedia</u>

UK: May 2021 to Present

H&S TECHNICAL ADVISOR, TRAINER AND AUDITOR

Checkpoint Solutions

UK: August 2007 to September 2009 - July 2014 to July 2016 - May 2019 to May 2020

H&S TECHNICAL ADVISOR, TRAINER AND AUDITOR

SGS Madrid

Spain: July 2016 - March 2019

CUSTOMER SERVICE MANAGER

OPRO Ltd

Spain: April 2011 - July 2014

CUSTOMER SERVICE MANAGER

Enterprise-Rent-A-Car

Spain: April 2010 - April 2011

CERTIFICATES

- → NEBOSH General Certificate
- → Principles of Fire Safety
- → COVID-19: Infection Prevention & PPE
- → Level 3 Award in Supervising Food Safety in Catering
- → Auditor Training School Travel Forum
- → Travel-life Sustainability in Tourism
- → Legionella and Legionnaires Disease Awareness

LANGUAGES







SPANISH (C1)

EDUCATION

Music Production - BSc(Hons) University of Greenwich

- → Music Production BA(Hons)
- → Music Production (HND)